# Daniel Duclos-Cavalcanti

516-912-7975 | New York, NY | U.S. Citizen | me@duclos.dev | linkedin/duclos-cavalcanti | github.com/duclos-cavalcanti

#### SUMMARY

Finding a thesis topic at the intersection of finance and computer science naturally complemented my rigorous German education in electrical engineering, leading me to the mentorship of Dr. Sivaraman at NYU. Today I am living in New York, completing a master's degree via an exciting research collaboration that envisions a future financial exchange on the cloud.

# **EDUCATION**

# Technical University of Munich

Munich, Germany & New York, USA

M.Sc. Electrical and Computer Engineering

Oct 2020 - Sept 2024

- External M.Sc. Thesis: VM Selection Heuristic for Multicast Overlay Trees in the Cloud
- Coursework: Embedded Design for Machine Learning, High Performance Computing for Machine Intelligence New York University

  New York, USA

Computer Science - Visiting Non-Degree Graduate Student

Sept 2023 - May 2024

- Co-Authored Publication: Jasper: Fair Multicast for Financial Exchanges in the Cloud
- CSCI-GA 2250 Operating Systems A

#### Technical University of Munich

Munich, Germany

B.Sc. Electrical and Computer Engineering

Oct 2016 - Sept 2020

#### EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

Jul 22 – Oct 22

TU Munich

Munich, Germany

- Evaluated and compared the performance of various Machine Learning models across GPUs, CPUs and TPUs.
- Analyzed USB traffic through PyShark between the host and externally added TPUs.
- Generated reports to establish a Design-Space Exploration framework to guide future model deployment decisions.

#### Embedded Engineer Intern

Aug 2021 – Jan 2022

Molabo GmbH Ottobrunn, Germany

- Developed internal tooling for state simulations through Linux's virtual CAN interface and mock APIs.
- Added unit-tests and code coverage to safety critical features of their motor drive embedded controller.
- Extended an automatic firmware update functionality used by over 20 clients.
- Automated build and testing workflows via Jenkins and CMake utilized by over 10 engineers.

# Tutor - Embedded Systems Programming Lab

Apr 2021 - Aug 2021

 $TU\ Munich$ 

Munich, Germany

• Supervised and aided 20+ students on their final embedded FreeRTOS laboratory projects in C.

# Publications

### Jasper: Fair Multicast for Financial Exchanges in the Cloud | (Paper)

Jan 2024 – Present

- Novel cloud hosted financial exchange achieving low latency multicast service for up to 1000 market participants.
- Achieves better scalability and around 50% lower latency than the multicast service provided by AWS.
- Used kernel-bypass techniques (DPDK) to achieve ultra-low latency at up to 35K multicast packet rate.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, C++, Python, Golang, Rust, Bash, Lua, VHDL, Tcl, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Tools: Terraform, Docker, Packer, AWS, GCP, Git, Unix Shell, Makefile, CMake, Linux, Jenkins, Vim

Technologies: Cloud Computing, Computer Networking, Embedded Systems, FPGA, RTOS, Machine Learning, HPC

Frameworks: ZeroMQ, DPDK, Tensorflow, TFLite, Numpy, Pandas, OpenMPI, OpenMP, Xilinx Vivado

Protocols: TCP, UDP, IP, USB, UART

Certificates: UCSD: Data Structures Fundamentals, UT Austin: Embedded Systems - uC I/O

## Projects

### Open-MPI Value Iteration | C++, Multi-Threaded, HPC

<u>Github</u> | 2022

• Asynchronous value iteration model to distribute workload on an HPC cluster.

# Hamming Code Error Detection | C, VHDL, FPGA, SoC

Github | 2022

• Error detection/correction algorithm for packet transmission on Microsemi's SF2 FPGA/SoC.

# FreeRTOS-SpaceInvaders | C, RTOS, Multi-Threaded

Github | 2021

• Implemented the famous arcade game as a multi-threaded FreeRTOS application in C.